<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[TechReg]]></title>
  <link href="http://dukeran.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dukeran.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-02T11:17:44-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://dukeran.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kerrie Durham]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Glimpse of the Amazon]]></title>
    <link href="http://dukeran.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/what-to-pack/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-02T08:50:50-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://dukeran.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/what-to-pack</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>Dream Come True</h4>

<div id="container">
<br>
<center><img src="http://i.imgur.com/hvoCq6X.png"  alt="Photo Credits to Charlotte Newell" height="250" width="250" style="margin:10px 10px">
</center>
</div>


<p>Ever since I was young, I had dreamed about going to the Amazon. Something about the river always made me imagine of adventure - of trekking through the jungle in search of a lost city. My grandfather used to buy me National Geographic magazines when I first learned to read and I remember staring at the pictures and cutting out the ones of the Amazon to tape up all over my wall, to the frustration of my parents. As I got older, My room was covered with world maps, each map marked with circles of where I would someday travel, always a big black line tracing the Amazon.</p>

<p>And there it was. The Amazon.</p>

<p>The section we were flying over was winding, brown, and languid, stretching as far as the eye could see with nothing but tropical canopy to match.</p>

<!--more-->


<h5>A few facts about the Amazon:</h5>

<ul>
<li>The second longest River in the world, accounts for 1/5 of the world&rsquo;s total river flow</li>
<li>The Amazon flows through Brazil</li>
<li>The Amazon is the rainforest&rsquo;s highway, providing transportation, trade, and communication between communities</li>
<li>Many of the Amazon port cities are only accessible by water or air</li>
<li>During the flood season, the Amazon fertilizes the surrounding soil</li>
<li>The Amazon River is a source of food for the communities living on the banks</li>
<li>Home of the Amazon river dolphin</li>
</ul>


<p>Thankfully living in Florida prepared Charlotte and I for the humidity that hit us as we disembarked the plane when it landed in Iquitos. The airport was small and there was dust everywhere. We climbed into our first South American rickshaw and gave the driver our hostel&rsquo;s name. With all the dust, dogs, and kids running around in dirty clothes it was hard to believe that Iquitos was once home to rubber barons, an opera house, and great mansions. Some of the mansions still stand today, but only as shadows of their former glory. Those were not necessarily good times for Iquitos, however. The rubber boom of the early 19th century meant wealth but it also meant that many companies such as the Peruvian Amazon Company (rubber company ) horrifically abused workers in the depths of the Amazon. Now, Iquitos serves as one of the main trading hubs of the Amazon, a center for timber, oil and mineral resources. Not to mention, Iquitos has a booming tourist industry as people from all over the world want to catch a glimpse of one of the seven natural wonders of the world; the Amazon River.</p>

<p>The second we registered our names in to the hostel leger, we were ushered into a common room and told to wait a few moments. A older woman from Spain joined us and before long a native from Iquitos introduced himself and gave us a pitch for a three-day adventure into the Amazon. Charlotte kept elbowing me in the ribs because I could hardly keep my eyes open and my head kept falling onto her shoulder. I was exhausted from the red-eye flight to Iquitos &hellip; and from the fact that we hadn&rsquo;t slept the night before because we we had been celebrating the opening of a new club down in Lima with new friends.</p>

<p>Raul, the Iquitian, was from a local travel company geared towards tourists and he told us about piranha fishing, swimming in the amazon, sleeping in hammocks, etc. A trip that sounded honestly amazing to me. Charlotte and I had looked online at possible Amazon tours but the prices had been outrages - ranging anywhere from $400 (if you were lucky) to $800 for a two night, three-day trek into the rainforest. Since our budget was limited, we decided to hold off before deciding on any $400 trek.</p>

<p>Everything Raul said sounded great, but just wait for it&hellip;and there! The price <strong>$500</strong>. Uh huh, no way. I was ready to gather my bags and head up to our rooms for a much needed nap when the lady from Spain, Mari Carmen came into play. She grabbed our hands, told Raul how we were family and that we should receive a discount since the three of us came together. She was nitpicky, arguing that the individual prices for each event would only cost so-and-so and that she might as well hire a native Iquitian to give us a personal tour instead of a local tour company. Little by little Raul lowered the prices until we were looking at $250 each for the entire three days, all meals included, and an extra excursion added on. The three of us jumped on it.</p>

<p>After money and handshakes were transferred (business was done with a word oath and then later with receipts) Mari Carmen winked at us and told us that we owed her one. We sure did!</p>

<p>At this point, both Charlotte and I were exhausted. We grabbed a quick lunch of fried fish in the town plaza and then lazily made our way back to our room to recover from the night before.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[From Lima to the Amazon]]></title>
    <link href="http://dukeran.github.io/blog/2016/02/08/virtual-cats/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-08T11:18:32-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://dukeran.github.io/blog/2016/02/08/virtual-cats</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>Virtual cats become dangerous</h4>

<p>  I am almost a week into my trip in Peru and I have yet to write a blog post about it! I never know how to start, should I write about reccommendations of where to go? Or should I just focus solely on Ruby and make a few mentions about Peru. I guess a blend of the two would be best. Then there&rsquo;s the struggle of finding time to write. My travel partner and I are always on the go, whether we&rsquo;re exploring Lima or trying new food.</p>

<div id="container">
<br>
<center><img src="http://i.imgur.com/wsK1Pf9.png"  alt="Ruins of Huaca Pucllana - ancient, pre-incan ruins which exist in the middle of Miraflores. It is a singularly odd experience to stand on ruins dating back to the first century C.E. while surrounded by high rise banks and apartments (Charlotte Newell)" height="300" width="300" style="margin:10px 10px">
</center>
</div>


<p>  The first five days we were in Lima, the capital city of Peru. I had packed for a full on winter with long underwear, fleece layers, wool socks, etc. only to find myself sweating in long pants and a T-shirt by noon. The weather is noticeably different from my hometown in Naples, Florida. Instead of constant sun, Lima has constant cloud cover. Clouds that loom low over the city and make it impossible to determine if it&rsquo;s raining or if you&rsquo;re constantly walking around in damp, ground-level clouds.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>  We stayed in the Miraflores district in a hostel called Pariwana which I would reccomend to anyone, however I can&rsquo;t say the same about Miraflores. Miraflores is a more modern and well-off district in Lima but it is full of USA fast-food chains and empty department stores. However, the bus station isn&rsquo;t far away and it is easy to get to downtown Lima where you can see catacombs and the governor&rsquo;s palace.</p>

<p>  The hostel we stayed in was always full of backpackers and trekkers from all over the world, though they tended to be Western, middle class, and experienced in the ways of backpacking. I have yet to meet anyone who says, &ldquo;this is my first trip abroad&rdquo;. I could have spent whole days in the hostel lounge area sitting on giant pillows and enjoying cups of coco tea while swapping stories with other backpackers. Everyone has a different perspective and have experienced different things while on the road and are happy to give reccommendations.</p>

<p>  In fact it is because of this interchange that Charlotte and I decided to completely go off our itinerary and take a flight towards Iquitos instead of Cusco. Charlotte and I had laid out a map of Peru and were discussing which bus to take and which hostels had the best deals over beer and cigars when someone mentioned that if we get a chance we should head towards Iquitos which is in the Peruvian rainforest and is only accessable by plane. Before long we were booking our flight out into the Amazon.</p>

<p>  While in the hostel in Lima, I tried to improve the program that I had written about in my last blog post about my cat, Thea. One evening I had brought out my laptop to have Charlotte give a go at trying to keep virtual Thea happy and well-fed (since sometimes my cat likes to have other people play with her than just me). Before long the laptop was being passed from person to person as everyone tried keep Thea content. It was a great way to find out which part of the code had bugs and how I could improve the program itself. Soon I made it where Thea could kill you if she became too hungry, if she became too bored, or if you didn&rsquo;t take her to the bathroom. I increased the difficulty and soon we were playing that whoever could survive the longest with my fierce cat would be the winner. This was definitely a great way to meet new people and to work on my code!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boolean Values]]></title>
    <link href="http://dukeran.github.io/blog/2016/02/07/boolean-values/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-07T00:44:33-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://dukeran.github.io/blog/2016/02/07/boolean-values</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>Fundamentals of Ones and Zeros</h4>

<p>Thanks to a friend of mine, I&rsquo;ve recently been doing a lot of Kata on <strong>Codewars</strong>. If you&rsquo;ve never done katas on Codewars before, I would <em>highly, highly, highly</em> recommend it. It&rsquo;s a great site where your competitive nature can get the best of you as you compete with other friends for &lsquo;honor&rsquo;. There are eight levels of difficulty and each kata is a creative coding problem that you solve for honor points. The beginner&rsquo;s level, level 8, is a good overview of incredibly basic coding concepts. Once you enter your solution you are able to see how others solved the same kata.</p>

<p>&ndash;> <a href="http://www.codewars.com">http://www.codewars.com</a></p>

<p>My username is <strong>dukeran</strong> if you want to add me!</p>

<h5><em>special note: if the same solution was posted by more than two people then I will not site the code.</em></h5>

<p>After going through Chris Pine&rsquo;s <em>Learn to Program</em>  book, here is the solution I came up with:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">boolean_to_string</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">b</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>          <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">b</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="kp">true</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="s2">&quot;true&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>          <span class="k">else</span> <span class="n">b</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="kp">false</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="s2">&quot;false&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>This is a straightforward code which works just fine but doesn&rsquo;t utilize the fundamental concept of Boolean values.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>It wasn&rsquo;t until I saw other answers and started doing some research that I learned more about it. It started when I saw the most popular answer and was instantly confused:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">boolean_to_string</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">b</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">b</span> <span class="p">?</span> <span class="s2">&quot;true&quot;</span> <span class="p">:</span> <span class="s2">&quot;false&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>At first I cocked my head and then wiped my glasses. First of all, what does the <code>?</code> mean? and why don&rsquo;t you have to specifically tell ruby that <code>if b = true...</code> How does ruby automatically know to test for true and false?</p>

<p>The program above may seem painfully simple to any programmer worth their salt but to a newbie in the field, it was a confusionfest - especially when it comes to Ruby. I find that as a Linguistics major with no background in coding, many expert programmers assume that these fundamentals are pure common sense. This is not the case for most non-programmers and I want to break everything down step by step.</p>

<h5>George Boole, the Foundation Layer</h5>

<p>Let&rsquo;s start with George Boole because I always find coding processes/fundamentals easier to swallow when the human element is added to make it a bit more personal. George Boole (1815-1864) was an Eglishman who is credited with laying the foundations for the informational age - the period that marked the shift from Industrial Revolution to what we have today with an economy based on information computerization. Without much formal teaching, he taught himeslf algebra and calculus using mathematics books. He became a prominent member of society and began publishing his own academic articles, lending insight into linear differential equations, invariant theory, and symbolic logic. Also, I learned that Boole is famous for using the term &ldquo;Universe of Discourse&rdquo; which is an important and fundamental concept to the linguistic study of pragmatics and semantics!!
In an attempt to systematize and categorize Airstotelian logic in order to be ableto extend its range of application, Boole created the beginnings of  Boolean logic.</p>

<h5>So What is the Difference Between Boolean logic and Aristotelian Logic?</h5>

<p>Aristotelian logic, or term logic, begins with the fundamental assumption that propositions are composed of two terms. The term is a part of speech which carries no truth value but instead represents something such as &ldquo;man&rdquo; or &ldquo;cat&rdquo;. The proposition is what consists of two terms, the &ldquo;affirmed&rdquo; or &ldquo;denied&rdquo; and the subject which is capable of true or false. Finally, the syllogism is the inference, or conclusion, that one can make from the premises.
Propositions can be either <strong>Universal and affirmative</strong>, <strong>Particular and affirmative</strong>, <strong>Universal and negative</strong>, or *Particular and negative**.</p>

<p>Fun Fact: Mary Everest Boole, his wife, was also a self-taught mathematician and was a strong advocate for teaching children Science at a young age and to make mathematics fun for the young. She often helped George Boole on his academic papers and attended conferences with him as well, unheard of for women of the time. She supported the idea that arithmetic was more anthropomorphic instead of purely abstract.</p>

<p>need to have a question mark to denote the boolean theory!!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upcoming Trip to South America ]]></title>
    <link href="http://dukeran.github.io/blog/2016/02/03/the-adventure-begins/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-03T18:56:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://dukeran.github.io/blog/2016/02/03/the-adventure-begins</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>How I coped with leaving my family and beginning my 2 month trip exploring South America - through code!</h4>

<p>And so it has begun! My friend Charlotte and I have boarded our flight for    Lima, the capital of Peru. Saying goodbye to my family and extended family brought tears to my eyes.</p>

<div id="container">
<br>
<center><img src="http://i.imgur.com/9AljWer.png"  alt="My own cat picture" height="300" width="300" style="margin:10px 10px">
</center>
</div>


<p>I couldn&rsquo;t help but feel bittersweet as we drove out   of my driveway towards the airport, leaving my family waving at the doorstep of   the house. Going on big trips is always bittersweet for me, I always hate   saying goodbye to those I love but at the same time I can&rsquo;t wait for another   adventure to begin. For me, there is nothing like new sites to see and new   experiences to be had, all the while meeting new and interesting people.</p>

<p>Like most other people on the internet, I&rsquo;m obsessed with my cat. She is my   pride and joy, even if she can be a bit peevish sometimes. I swear, with the   rate of cat pictures being uploaded daily, the percentage of Mr. Whiskers   pictures might surpass the amount of porn to be found on the web.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Since I am going to miss my little feline buddy, I decided to practice some of   my new coding skills, using the few tools I have in my tool kit. In the   following code (with the help of Chris Pine&rsquo;s example as a template) I created a   little virtual cat that I can take care of while I&rsquo;m away from my living, breathing fuzzball. I named the program Thea, after my precious fuzzball.</p>

<p><strong>The items I used in my recently aquired tool kit:</strong>
<em>variables
</em>loops
<em>recursion
</em>creating a new class
*defining methods</p>

<p>And&hellip;that about sums up my entire tool kit. Hopefully one day that list will   be longer!</p>

<p>My most recently aquired tool is <em>defining a class</em>. A brand new and exciting   concept. This time I initialized the <code>class Pet</code>
Note that class remains lowercase while the new class that you are initializing   is capitalized. One thing that was stressed in Chris Pine&rsquo;s book is the   difference between <code>new</code> and <code>initialize</code>. It&rsquo;s not a horribly confusing   concept but I want to go over it real quick. <code>new</code> comes first. You cannot   initialize something that has not yet been created! <code>new</code> creates the objet   that the computer will then <code>initialize</code>. <code>new</code> creates the object only, it is   never used again while <code>initialized</code> needs to be defined because you need to   explain to your poor computer what you want to do with this brand new object.   You can only use <code>new</code> to <em>create</em> a new object, if you use <code>initialize</code> in   order to create a new object, the computer will freak out, looking for some    nonexistant object to start up, and will spit out a panic-stricken error code.   Yes, personalizing the computer and its languages makes it easier for me to   understand, hopefully it does for you too!</p>

<p>This one <code>class</code> is 155 lines long and it only takes one to initialize it and  to get it running.</p>

<p>Within the <code>class</code> I have defined over seven different methods;
* <code>initialize</code>
* <code>feed</code>
* <code>play</code>
* <code>walk</code>
* <code>put_to_bed</code>
* <code>code</code></p>

<p>In each <code>def</code> (define) I clearly lay out the groundworks for how I want the   computer to respond in different scenarios. In this code I only have two   possible environments; asleep and not asleep. I can only imagine this makes it   easier to keep track of all the possiblities and possible behaviors. I   definitely suggest if you try writing this code for practice and you&rsquo;re new   like me, start with only two different possible scenarios until you&rsquo;re able to   effortlessly keep track of all the different possibilities.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s one thing that confused me when I first read the template and started   writing my own program. What the heck does &ldquo; <code>@variable</code> mean? In the first 5   lines of code there is this new symbol that I&rsquo;ve never used before: &rdquo;<code>@</code>&ldquo;. Much   confused. I decided to look it up and explain it to other newbies: the <code>@</code> signifies an instance variable of the specific class. It is important because it only functions within the class and you use it to tell the computer that you want something done in that particular instance. It&rsquo;s also cool because it is the same variable but at different defined instances you assign it a different value.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a quick snippet from one of the <code>def</code> methods:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">feed</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Thea purrs as you pick up her food bag.&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">&quot;She winds in between your legs as you put a handful of food into her food bowl.&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="vi">@stuffinbelly</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">5</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">passageoftime</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">peeve</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>I think in the big picture this is an amazing thing about Ruby. This is line 13 to 20 of the code. I have in no way defined the variable <code>passageoftime</code> or <code>peeve</code>. I don&rsquo;t  define them until line 91 and line 125. To me, this is so not intuitive.  Imagine going up to someone and being like &ldquo;Remember that blubber story?&rdquo; and   then laugh. That person is going to look at you like you&rsquo;ve lost your freaking   mind because s/he has no context or no idea what you could possibly be   referring to. Later that day you walk up to that same person and tell him/her  a hilarious story about how you were living with some Inuits up in Alaska and you   thought the blubber they offered you was ice cream until you took your first   bite. Now this person has context and can laugh with you. But this is only after you have taken a random variable of &ldquo;blubber&rdquo; and put it into a context.   It doesn&rsquo;t need to work this way with Ruby! You do the same thing with   Ruby and she will know to laugh earlier in the day even before you told the   blubber story just because you told it later that day. It&rsquo;s as if Ruby is living in a world where she processes your code so fast that time doesn&rsquo;t   exist in a linear fashion. Whether something happens in the past or in the   future doesn&rsquo;t matter to it, as long as it is all in that one instance of code.   If this isn&rsquo;t cool to you, then well, you lack imagination and excitement in   your life&hellip;</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/bIMAIO2.png" alt="Taking the fuzzball for a swim and a walk" /></p>

<p>A new thing I learned while writing this code is the (method/function?)   <code>private</code>. It means that the following code and its functions can only be   modified in the code itself and the user running the program can&rsquo;t access it.   It&rsquo;s like the hidden part of the code that is running behind the scenes and   makes the interface run smoothly.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the loop that I threw into my code!</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">ask</span> <span class="n">question</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">thea</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="no">Pet</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">new</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Thea&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">while</span> <span class="kp">true</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="n">question</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">reply</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nb">gets</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">chomp</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">reply</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s1">&#39;feed&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="n">thea</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">feed</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">elsif</span> <span class="n">reply</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s1">&#39;walk&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="n">thea</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">walk</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">elsif</span> <span class="n">reply</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s1">&#39;put to bed&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="n">thea</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">puttobed</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">elsif</span> <span class="n">reply</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s1">&#39;pick up&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="n">thea</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">pickup</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">elsif</span> <span class="n">reply</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s1">&#39;code&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="n">thea</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">code</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">elsif</span> <span class="n">reply</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s1">&#39;play&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="n">thea</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">play</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">else</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s1">&#39;I\&#39;m sorry, but that is beyond virtual Thea\&#39;s capabilities.&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>I love the concept of <code>while true</code>. I&rsquo;m sure a lot could be written about just   that one concept but I&rsquo;m tired and this kid behind me keeps hitting my seat  and crying. Has anyone ever been on a flight without any kids? I feel as if that  is as rare as finding a wild unicorn.
Anyways I used this loop here in order to keep the program continuing until it   terminates on its own either because the virtual cat becomes too hungry or too   peevish. My cat can become a monster when she is cranky and peeved by us   humans messing with her, so I decided that the program would end if she became   too upset with the human interacting with her. No one likes a grumpy, cranky   cat, unless of course you&rsquo;re the owner of Grumpy Cat and you&rsquo;re making it rain   from all the royalties.
One thing that I really enjoy about this loop is it&rsquo;s incredibly simple and   that you can keep piling on the <code>elsif</code>. Truly, as many as you want. As long   as the <code>if</code> gets a counter <code>else</code> and you put the correct number of <code>ends</code> all   is good in the computer world.</p>

<p>The link to my full code can be found <a href="https://github.com/dukeran/thea">here on github</a>! I&rsquo;ll also write a post   about how I got github to work for me, since it&rsquo;s not user friendly to those  who are new to the tech world.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Congratulations! A baby Thea has been born! You can do a lot of cool</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="s1">  things with this interactive, virtual Thea while you\&#39;re away. You need to</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="s1">  take good care of her and make sure she goes to the bathroom and eats well.</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="s1">  Here are some of the things you can do with Thea:</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="s1">    1. feed</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="s1">    2. walk</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="s1">    3. put to bed</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="s1">    4. pick up</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="s1">    5. play</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="s1">    6. code - you can even practice your coding while she\&#39;s around!&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="kp">nil</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s1">&#39;What would you like to do with Thea?&#39;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>P.S. I would like to note that I am going to miss my family more than
my cat but it felt weird writing a code in which I fed my sister and
would have to take her to go to the bathroom. &lt;3 you Lanjing!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upcoming Trip to South America ]]></title>
    <link href="http://dukeran.github.io/blog/2016/02/03/upcoming-trip-to-south-america/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-03T17:56:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://dukeran.github.io/blog/2016/02/03/upcoming-trip-to-south-america</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>How I am going to keep track of everything</h4>

<p>I am counting down the days until I board my flight to the captial of Peru!! I wrote a small program that will display my statement of purpose, my itinerary, and how many more days I have left until my return flight. Since Archer is one of my favorite TV shows, I often run my programs under the name of Woodhouse and he is incredibly helpful. In this blog post I&rsquo;ve linked my incredibly simple program to github so you guys can take a look!
The beginning was easy. I tried to use a little bit of everything I&rsquo;ve learned in the first ten chapters of <em>Learn to Code</em> by Chris Pine.</p>

<p>I used my first array:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="n">options</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="o">[[</span><span class="s1">&#39;Statement of Purpose&#39;</span><span class="o">]</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>                  <span class="o">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;Itinerary&#39;</span>           <span class="o">]</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>                  <span class="o">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;Days Left &#39;</span>       <span class="o">]]</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<!--more-->


<p>I have to admit, I&rsquo;m still a little confused on what exactly an array is. Chris Pine usually does an excellent job explaining things so I&rsquo;m not sure if I&rsquo;m just unusually thick or if array&rsquo;s are actually a hard concept for a newbie to understand right away.</p>

<p>After doing a little research, it seems to me that an array is listing of objects which all share a common element. The computer is able to see them as individual units but also as a singular group unit which is valuable when you&rsquo;re dealing with a large amount of objects. EXAMPLE two different groups of objects and the comp has to deal with them in seperate ways.</p>

<p>Here comes Woodhouse!!</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
<span class='line-number'>26</span>
<span class='line-number'>27</span>
<span class='line-number'>28</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Hello Miss, my name is Woodhouse and I am here to help you with your trip.</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="s1">Please choose from the following options&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="kp">nil</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">op_num</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">1</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">options</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">each</span> <span class="k">do</span> <span class="o">|</span><span class="n">op</span><span class="o">|</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nb">name</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">op</span><span class="o">[</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="o">]</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">beginning</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">op_num</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">to_s</span> <span class="o">+</span> <span class="s1">&#39;. &#39;</span> <span class="o">+</span> <span class="nb">name</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="n">beginning</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">ljust</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">30</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">op_num</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">op_num</span> <span class="o">+</span> <span class="mi">1</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="kp">nil</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">ask</span> <span class="n">question</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="n">question</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">reply</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nb">gets</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">chomp</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">downcase</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">reply</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s1">&#39;statement of purpose&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>            <span class="no">STATEMENT</span> <span class="no">OF</span> <span class="no">PURPOSE</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="k">elsif</span> <span class="n">reply</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s1">&#39;itinerary&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s1">&#39;long list of itinerary&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="k">elsif</span> <span class="n">reply</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s1">&#39;days left&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s1">&#39;t-lift off&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">else</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="kp">nil</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Miss, please refer to the options above and choose one of the following.&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">ask</span> <span class="n">question</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="kp">nil</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">ask</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Miss, which would you like to know about?&#39;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>I love the <code>def</code> function, which is just short for &lsquo;define&rsquo;. IF there is one thing I&rsquo;m certain about, is that programmers will find the laziest way to type/do everything. As James explained it to me, the define function is like creating a written contract with your computer. You tell it that under these circumstances I want you to do the following&hellip; And you explain in detail exactly how you want it to behave. I love it! It allows for so much creativity. So the <code>def</code> alerts the computer/program that you&rsquo;re are about to give it its contract. The <code>ask</code> is the actual command that you define and will use in the future, while <code>question</code> is the variable that you&rsquo;ll define after the contract is written. In the code I wrote above, the <code>'Miss, which would you like to know about?'</code> is how I decided to define the varibale <code>question</code>.</p>

<p>Another thing that I would like to point out to other newbie coders of Ruby is that <code>elsif</code> is a subset of the <code>if</code> function, and that <code>else</code> is the counterpart to the <code>if</code>. You can fit as many <code>elsif</code>s as you want under <code>if</code> but you can&rsquo;t keep piling on the <code>else</code>s after the <code>if</code>. One <code>if</code> and one <code>else</code> within a loop. I learned that after much frustration.</p>

<p>The second part of the code is the following:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Would you like to know about anything else?&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">replytwo</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nb">gets</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">chomp</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">downcase</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">replytwo</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s1">&#39;yes&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">ask</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Miss, which would you like to know about?&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">elsif</span> <span class="n">replytwo</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s1">&#39;no&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="kp">nil</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Very well Miss, have a good day.&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="kp">nil</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">else</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="kp">nil</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Please choose one of the options mentioned above.&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="n">ask</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Miss, which would you like to know about?&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>This was actually the hardest part of the code. I spent more time on this part than I should have because I kept crashing my computer. I made the mistake of putting in</p>

<p><code>ruby
while
        true
    if reply == 'yes' ...etc
   </code></p>

<p>Which made my computer have a panic attack as it tried to compute the huge motherload of tasks I had just given it. To repeat the loop infinatum. Impossible, so my computer took the easy way out and committed suicide every time. Poor thing. I just removed the <code>while true</code> and it fixed everything.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Arsenal]]></title>
    <link href="http://dukeran.github.io/blog/2016/02/03/my-arsenal/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-03T16:56:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://dukeran.github.io/blog/2016/02/03/my-arsenal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In about a week I will be taking a one way flight to Lima, Peru armed with nothing more than a daypack and the smallest Dell Chromebook I have ever seen. For the past month before my trip I have been familiarizing myself with the chromebook and with Chris Pine&rsquo;s <em>Learn to Program</em> (second edition).</p>

<div id="container">
<center><img src="http://imgur.com/Yu5aRuC.jpg" alt="Thanks Pine!" height="200" width="200" style="margin:20px 20px">
</center>
<p>
</p>
</div>


<h4>The Technology: Dell CRM3120-1667BLK 11.6" Chromebook</h4>

<p>This has been my favorite laptop that I have ever used. Granted, I haven&rsquo;t used more than probably 3 clunky old laptops but I can gaurantee that this is undoubtably my favorite. It&rsquo;s small, fast, spill proof (incredibly important when it comes to me), and it isn&rsquo;t loaded down with stupid and unecessary programs. All this for the price $199.99 on Amazon which makes it a steal unless you&rsquo;re planning to use it for gaming&hellip;but I don&rsquo;t know much about that since I&rsquo;m all about the Xbox.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>So far this laptop has worked great for the few things that I need a laptop to do; browse reddit, code Ruby, watch Archer, and stream&hellip;videos. Thankfully my friend James Gibson was able to install chroot in order for us to play with the linux system and install Ruby.
If anyone is interested in the chromebook, here&rsquo;s the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00FBBUIDM/ref=psdc_565108_t1_B00K1FY3M0">link</a> for it on Amazon</p>

<p><img src="http://imgur.com/utWYQ0K.jpg" alt="Front view" />
<img src="http://imgur.com/GCpqHm9.jpg" alt="Back view" /></p>

<h4>Knowledge is Power: <em>Learn to Program</em> second edition by Chris Pine</h4>

<p>When James first lent me this book, it was pristine and the spine unbroken. Now it lays here, dog-eared, marked, highlighted, and coffee stained (that&rsquo;s why the spill-proof laptop was so valuable). I have read it cover to cover and overall I would give it an excellent rating. The beginning 8 chapters are phenomenal; easy to read and even made me chuckle. His smooth writing and horrible jokes made the book fun and actually motivated me to do the challenging assignments at the end of each chapter. However, chapter 9 left me feeling abandoned and inccapable as he leaped into more complicated coding without any actual teaching. Chapter 9 and on had me pulling my hair and asking my friends for help constantly because in my mind it was either sink or swim. However, I kept at it and when I finished the book I definitely beleived that the book was 100% worth it. It serves as an excellent reference guide and opened the door to how coders think and the problems they face. It also served as an excellent foundation to someone who has never had an inkling of coding before in her life.</p>

<p>His chapters and the concepts he covered are as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li>Numbers - Integers and Floats</li>
<li>Strings</li>
<li>puts, gets, and chomp methods</li>
<li>branching</li>
<li>looping</li>
<li>arrays</li>
<li>Classes - hash class and time class</li>
<li>Methods that take and return procs</li>
</ul>


<p>As a newbie coder, some of the concepts were harder than others. I&rsquo;m still trying to wrap my head around arrays and how they exactly work. But overall, I must say thanks to Chris Pine for his excellent introduction.</p>

<p><img src="http://imgur.com/Yu5aRuC.jpg" alt="Thanks Pine!" /></p>

<p>In a few days I will be using another book/source in order to continue learning while in Peru. I definitely still have a lot of qustions that hopefully I&rsquo;ll figure out as I learn more about Ruby, such as what is YAML and why do developers love recursive acronyms so much?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction to the Traveling Code]]></title>
    <link href="http://dukeran.github.io/blog/2016/01/26/introduction/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-26T16:56:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://dukeran.github.io/blog/2016/01/26/introduction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>The beginning of <em>Traveling Code</em></h3>

<div id="container">
<center><img src="http://i.imgur.com/afjR3yl.jpg" alt="The Sahara on camelback" height="200" width="200" style="margin:20px 20px">
</center>
</div>


<p>Life is full of surprises. Four years ago, if I was told that one day I would be writing a travel blog about coding, I would have laughed. Four years ago I was herding cows in the Atlas mountains in Morocco, living with the Berber people in a tiny village that didn&rsquo;t have running water, let alone internet or computers. Even up to a couple of months ago I hadn&rsquo;t the slightest idea of what coding entailed or what Ruby even was&hellip;</p>

<p>One night, a good friend of mine started pitching the idea of coding over a couple of beers. It was cold outside and the two tankards of Blue Moon had warmed me up to the idea of learning a computer language. After all, I thought, I am a linguistics student, learning a computer language can&rsquo;t be all that difficult after my experiences learning languages such as Chinese and Russian. Boy, was I wrong. <!--more-->
After just a few weeks with my <em>Learning to Program</em> by Chris Pine, I quickly discovered that learning to code is a whole different animal. Not only are you learning how to create code in order to communicate to the computer but you also have to learn how it thinks. I no longer consider sorting words in alphabetical order to be an easy task. Things that I had taken for granted such as defining &lsquo;word&rsquo; and the idea of compiling a list has had me pulling my hair out as my code would fail again and again. But it is through these failures that I have learned what I know about precious Ruby and have come to realize that so far I am actually thoroughly enjoying myself.</p>

<p>In less than a month I&rsquo;ll be doing what I was born to do; traveling. Every summer and every chance I get I pack my bag and head out to new country to explore life and all it has to offer from the riches of Chinese five star hotels to the rustic Moroccan village. Except this time it&rsquo;s going to be a bit different and my bag will weigh just a pound heavier as I travel with this tiny Dell Chromebook throughout the roads of Peru and Ecuador. While there, I&rsquo;m going to be learning to code everyday and writing about my experiences at least once a week. I&rsquo;m only at the initial stages of learning how to code and the more I study and practice the more I realize that there is so much still to learn. I&rsquo;m writing this blog as a way to keep myself disciplined and to track my progression as I conitnue to learn Ruby and travel. If you&rsquo;re reading this I hope you enjoy what follows and I would appreciate feedback since this is a new experience for me!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NanoWrimo: Introduction]]></title>
    <link href="http://dukeran.github.io/blog/2016/01/23/nanowrimo-introduction/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-23T12:22:19-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://dukeran.github.io/blog/2016/01/23/nanowrimo-introduction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Check out the introduction to the draft of the novel I wrote for NanoWrimo! Please give me some feedback so I can improve the writing style and write up some more drafts before publishing.</p>

<p><em>The bulky grey heart monitor recorded the irregular heart beat of a young girl as she laid in a hospital bed. The monitor flickered, creating an eerie glow around the girl that flashed in and out with each beat. The girl in question lay motionless, her brown hair, bunched in matted dreads from dirt and sweat, framed her gaunt face. Her big, almost sinister, grey eyes were fixed on the only other person in the room&hellip;
</em> <!--more-->&hellip;a skinny and frail man dressed in a white lab coat. He had just entered the small room just moments before. The man swallowed nervously and approached the bed, careful to position himself at least arms-length away&hellip;</p>

<p>The girl didnt move an inch but her eyes followed his every movement.
The man leaned forward an inch, Whats your name, sweetie? he said, his voice higher pitched than he had wanted. He cleared his throat.
The only answer was the heart monitor.
How old are you? He tried again, the hairs on the back of his neck standing on end.
The grey eyes flickered and she blinked but made no other movement.<br/>
Where were you before you came here? by now his heart was pounding against his rib cage, his hands clammy.</p>

<p>There was movement from the door and the man visibly jolted in fear. As the door opened, a tall woman entered the room, she too was wearing a labcoat and she walked towards the man with long, confident strides. Her lips were in a thin line and turned slightly downwards in frustration. The man turned to her, unable to hide his feelings of relief at having someone else at his side.
Baptiste, sir, said the man and with his new found confidence, he turned to Baptiste and asked, Is she stupid or just plain mute?
The woman stood beside the man, seeming to ponder his question as she stared at the young girl. The silence in the room was almost unbearable, and the heart monitor only made it worse.
Leave, said Baptiste, her voice carrying the authority of a leader and she never once took her eyes off the girl.
The man didnt need to be told twice and he exited the room with as much fanfare as he had entered.
When the man left the room, the girls owlish eyes shifted towards the woman who was now at her bedside. Baptiste didnt say a word, if this was going to be a waiting game, then she would wait with all the patience in the world. At last, a small but steady voice was heard, I have a message for Andrea Parks.
Baptiste completely pale but retained her composure, A message for whom?
Andrea Parks, came the measured reply. The grey eyes didnt reveal any emotion.
What is the message?
I dont know, but I have to deliver it to Andrea Parks.
Baptiste glanced up at the wall for a few seconds and then brought her gaze back down to look upon the young girl, Andrea Parks was executed for treason five years ago.
A look of surprise flashed through the girls eyes before she quickly closed them. With a faint whisper she said, but Andrea Parks is my mother.
After hearing those words, Baptiste turned on her heels and all but fled from the sparse hospital room into the grimy hallway where a fluorescent light flickered, the door slamming behind her.
Just outside the room, two scientists waited.
Baptiste barked orders, I want a full physical done on this girl, I want to know exactly how old she is, where she comes from, and how the fuck she knows Andrea Parks.&ldquo;
Yes Ms. Baptiste, sir The other two acknowledged her orders and swiftly went down the hallway.
Baptiste furrowed her brow as she leaned against the wall that separated her from the girl on the other side. All she could hear was the incessant beeping and her thoughts wandered back to the painful memories of her past. Oh, Andrea&hellip;she whispered to herself as she slid down the wall, drew her knees up and cupped her head in her hands.</p>

<p>There was a knock on the door.
Come in, Baptiste put down her travel logs that she had just been furiously looking through and looked down her glasses as one of the scientists entered the small cozy room. Baptiste sat in an armchair, a small lamp casting a warm glow on a wooden desk and a framed picture of a forest that hung on the other wall. The scientist sat on the other side of the desk in a chair that constituted the only other piece of furniture in the room.
Doctor Sanders didnt say anything as he slid five polaroid photos across the table. Baptiste picked up the photos and looked at each one intently before saying, Show me.
Doctor Sanders led the way as the two walked down the hallway just a few doors down. He opened the door and Baptiste noted that two more monitors were hooked up to the girl, the cords disappearing under the blanket that she had pulled up to her chin. Doctor Sanders approached the bed and, without saying anything, ripping back the sheet from the girls body, revealing her naked torso. Baptiste drew in a sharp intake of breath, Son of a bitch!
The gaunt eyes of the young girl looked defiantly up at Baptiste and she made no move to cover herself.
Her torso was covered in black marks the resembled circuitry as they spread like tendrils from her heart to her extremities. They covered her entire left side and faded back into the skin as the tendrils reached out from the heart.
Sanders began his report as Baptistes eyes followed the shape of the markings. The labwork says she is exactly twelve years old as of today. Baptiste gave him a look of is that all you could find out? He continued, due to her&hellip;irregularities we analyzed her DNA sequence and we found something quite astounding. Sanders led the way back out of the hallway into a lab next door. Clearly the most expensive room in the dilapidated hospital, the lights shone brightly upon all the top quality machines that buzzed softly. Sanders and Baptiste now stood in front of a three panel monitor; one monitor was running DNA sequences, the other one was running numbers, and the third was slowly typing out words. Sometimes the third monitor would type three letters, pause, and then continue at a halting pace. (Little by little  want a different phrase) it was possible to tease out the words being written out and then the sentences that followed.
Sanders turned to Baptiste, A message has been encoded into her DNA.
He continued, The girl is not only the messenger but also the message.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
